Simran Garcha

9059242016 • Oshawa, Ontario (L1J2E1) • garcha.simran2000@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/simran-garcha-03216616b

WEBSITE PORTFOLIO

https://simrangarcha.com/

UX & UI Designer

Creative | Commited | Philomath

Enthusiastic Graphic and Web Designer with the ability to collaborate in a rapidly changing environment. Love to keep adding to current skillset and exploring new options. I have had experience in Creating Introduction Videos using After Effects, Creating Illustrations, posters, wireframes, and web designs. Comfortable with digital media and design trends. Implemented those designs using HTML and CSS, further learning new skills to add animation to make it more User friendly and Attractive. Passionate about art and fashion.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SUBWAY- Ajax, Ontario

Oct 2021-Present

STORE MANAGER

Responsible for developing store strategies to raise customer's pool, expand store traffic and optimize profitability.

- Establishing Work Schedules
- Maintaining record of stocks, sales, wastage
- Training new employees in job responsibilities, sanitation and customer dealing to ensure customer satisfaction.
- Maintaining Restaurant Quality Standards
- Responsible for the hiring new staff members.
- Dealing with customer issues, maintaining of equipment in store and problem-solving
- Handling POS updates and responsible for promotion installations.
- Creating Word Documentation for the office and for Instructions purpose.

DURHAM COLLEGE -Oshawa, Ontario

March 2021 - May 2021

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Worked in a team of Five to create an AR Application using AR.js, Three.js, HTML and CSS. The app required brainstorming and sharing of ideas to create the application.

Created wireframes and did prototyping

- Co-ordinated with the Backend Developer and Graphic Designing Team to Create the app.
- Implemented the design provided by the Graphic Team using HTML and CSS.
- Worked along-side the Backend Developer to create the components in a manner which is user-friendly, and the functions can be added easily.

DURHAM COLLEGE -Oshawa, Ontario

January 2021- April 2021

WORDPRESS DEVELOPER & TEAM LEADER

Team Lead in the development & implementation of graphic layout and production communication while meeting the client's needs.

- Supervised the assessment of all graphic materials to ensure quality and accuracy of the design.
- Communication with the design team to create a better understanding of the requirements of the client.
- Testing the responsiveness of the website and the SEO standards checklist.
- Making small tweaks throughout the process according to the client's desires

EDUCATION

DURHAM COLLEGE – Oshawa, Ontario

Diploma in Contemporary Web Designing (January 2020- April 2022)

ORANE INTERNATIONAL – Chandigarh, India

Diploma in Contemporary Web Designing (January 2019- December 2019)

ALLIANCE FRANCAISE – Chandigarh, India

Certification in French (A1 & A2) (September 2018- January 2019)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- MICROSOFT OFFICE: Excel, Word, PowerPoint
- ADOBE CREATIVE CLOUD: Illustrator, Photoshop, Premier Pro, After Effects, InDesign, Adobe XD, Lightroom, Dreamweaver, Acrobat
- OPERATING SYSTEM: MacOS, Microsoft Windows
- DESIGNING: Procreate, Figma, Camera Handling (Photography)
- DEVELOPMENT: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GitHub, PHP, WordPress, WooCommerce, MySQL, jQuery, Micro Bit
- COLLABORATION PROGRAMS: Asana

- SOCIAL MEDIA: Instagram, Pinterest, Snapchat
- FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES: Bootstrap, Materialize, Foundation, GSAP, THREE.js, React
- Able to design mock-ups for webpages and social media banners.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Able to quickly grasp new concepts.
- Leadership and Teamwork Skills.
- Excellent Communication, Listening and Organizational skills
- Strategic Thinker and ensures deadlines are met, goals are achieved.
- Positive and confident attitude with a flair for detail and organization.
- Ability to multitask, manage and prioritize several projects in an on-going basis.
- Have a strong visual design sensibility and work well in a collaborative environment.
- Proven time management abilities as well as strong analytical and technical knowledge.
- The ability to work under pressure and adapt to change.

AWARDS AND HONORS

COLLEGE HONOURS – Durham College

June 2021

- Consistently made it on the Honors Roll three semester in a row; graduated with 4.25 GPA and Honors Roll.
- Worked closely with professors and advisors to complete assigned tasks and activities.

LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

English: fluent

• Hindi: fluent

• Punjabi: fluent

• French: beginner